<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on CloudNativePG - PostgreSQL Operator for Kubernetes</title>
    <link>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on CloudNativePG - PostgreSQL Operator for Kubernetes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daniel Chambre</title>
      <link>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/dchambre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/dchambre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A DBA and Open Source enthusiast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floor Drees</title>
      <link>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/fdrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/fdrees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open Source community advocate and Principal Program Manager at EDB. PostgreSQL Code of Conduct Committee member, PG EU Diversity Committee member, PGDay Lowlands organizer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gabriele Bartolini</title>
      <link>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/gbartolini/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/gbartolini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A long time open source programmer and entrepreneur, Gabriele has a degree in&#xA;Statistics from the University of Florence. After having consistently&#xA;contributed to the growth of 2ndQuadrant and its members through nurturing a&#xA;lean and devops culture, he is now leading the Cloud Native initiative at EDB.&#xA;Gabriele lives in Prato, a small but vibrant city located in the northern part&#xA;of Tuscany, Italy - known for having hosted the first European PostgreSQL&#xA;conferences. His second home is Melbourne, Australia, where he studied at&#xA;Monash University and worked in the ICT sector. He loves playing the Blues with&#xA;his Fender Stratocaster, but his major passions are called Elisabeth and&#xA;Charlotte!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Gonzalez V.</title>
      <link>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/jgonzalez/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/jgonzalez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A free software lover, passionate about OpenSource and all the tools that&#xA;it has created to help a lot of people build their dreams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Working at EDB to bring the real database experience to Kubernetes world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jaime Silvela</title>
      <link>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/jsilvela/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 22:34:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/jsilvela/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jaime Silvela has been around. In a long and varied career writing code,&#xA;he has lived in the US and Europe, worked for big corporations like Amazon and&#xA;Microsoft, as an early startup employee, in industries including Wall Street and&#xA;catastrophe insurance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early in his career he discovered a fondness for databases, PostgreSQL in&#xA;particular. He started using Go professionally in 2014, a relief after having&#xA;suffered the Java monoculture at Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leonardo Cecchi</title>
      <link>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/leonardoce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cloudnative-pg.io/authors/leonardoce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in computer science from the beginning, and programming has always&#xA;been my obsession. My passion began when I was 6 when my father taught me the&#xA;rudiments of C programming.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working in 2ndQuadrant since 2016 as a developer and a PostgreSQL&#xA;consultant. PostgreSQL has always been my choice when working with a DBMS. I’ve&#xA;been using it since 1998.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EDB acquired 2ndQuadrant in 2020, and CloudNativePG, the operator I&#xA;have been working on with my team since 2019, was finally released as OSS in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
